## CONTACT

# SHAIAH EMIGH-DOYLE

sde2111@columbia.edu

(207) 479-7090

Full-Stack Software Developer

NYC or Remote

shaiahwren.com

github.com/ShaiahWren

linkedin.com/in/shaiah-emigh-doyle

# **EDUCATION**

#### **DIGITALCRAFTS**

July 2020 - Nov 2020

Full-stack software development course for creating web applications with a JavaScript full-stack including Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, Python, HTML and CSS.

#### **COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY**

New York, NY 2018 - 2020 Master of Arts in Anthropology GPA: 3.90

#### **SMITH COLLEGE**

Northampton, MA 2012 - 2016 Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology & Arabic GPA: 3.92

# **SKILLS**

# Tools, Technologies, & Expertise

- Python
- JavaScript
- CSS/HTML
- Node.js
- Express
- PostgreSQL
- React/Redux
- Git/Github
- Responsive Design
- RESTful API
- Responsive Design

# Foreign Languages

- Hebrew
- Arabic
- Swahili
- Spanish
- English

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack developer dedicated to producing software and excellent user experience. A critical thinker with a passion for learning, an Anthropologist and linguist with international experience, I bring a diverse and unique set of skills to any project or team environment.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **DIGITAL CRAFTS**

Full-stack Software Developer | July 2020 - Nov 2020

## VivaLingua

 $\underline{\mathsf{jdevspace}.\mathsf{netlify}.\mathsf{app}} \mid \underline{\mathsf{github}.\mathsf{com/ShaiahWren/Study-App}} \mid \mathsf{September}$ 

#### 2020

• j.devspace is a resource for junior developers that neatly brings together interview prep, video coding tutorials, and the jobs search in an easy-to-use app. A back-end with express routes stores flashcards for JavaScript, Python, and React fundamentals in a database.

## VivaLingua

vivalingua.dev | github.com/ShaiahWren/Viva Lingua | September 2020

- Built a full-stack application for crowdsourcing information about four endangered languages.
- Primary team roles included PostgreSQL, Back-end & Front-end development, and Lead styling/design.

#### Quiz Yo'self

## <u>quiz-yoself.com</u> | <u>github.com/ShaiahWren/Quiz-Yoself</u> | August 2020

- Collaborated with three other developers to build a trivia website
- The application was built from scratch using vanilla JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and an API. Implemented all the design and styling elements and produced a fully responsive web application.

#### Fun Fair Danger

## github.com/ShaiahWren/fun fair danger | August 2020

- Worked on a team of four to build a terminal-based Python game.
- Took full responsibility for creating the 'wizard room,' in which I led the user through a series of riddles, interrogations, and cyphers.

More projects at: My Portfolio | My Github

## LENFEST CENTER FOR THE ARTS, COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

Wardrobe Technician | Sept 2019 - Nov 2020

Collaborated with costume designers, wardrobe supervisor, and student staff to create professional costumes for director thesis productions. Utilized hand stitching and machine sewing skills.